Guide to the Yoshito Fujii Papers 1942-1945
Special Collections, University of Washington Libraries
Yoshito Fujii Papers
1942-1945
University of Washington Libraries Special Collections
1582
Fujii, Yoshito
1 cubic foot plus 14 pages of textual materials
Issei businessman and civic leader who was removed from Seattle to the Minidoka Relocation Center in Idaho during World War II
Yoshito Fujii was a Seattle Issei hotel owner and civic leader. During the incarceration experience, he played an important role in the organization of a viable community at the Minidoka Relocation Center in Hunt, Idaho. He served as chairman of the first Board of Directors there and was later chairman of the Community Council.
The papers of Harry R. Hatate (folders 2 3) also document the maintenance worker labor dispute at Minidoka (volume 3 below).
The accession was donated to the Libraries by Yoshito Fujii on December 26, 1979.
Fujii, Yoshito--Archives; Myer, Dillon S. (Dillon Seymour), 1891-
Minidoka Relocation Center
Concentration camp inmates--Idaho--Hunt; Concentration camps--Idaho--Hunt; Concentration camps--Idaho--Hunt--Management; Japanese Americans--Evacuation and relocation, 1942-1945; World War, 1939-1945--Concentration camps--Idaho--Hunt; World War, 1939-1945--Japanese Americans
Civil Rights; Idaho; Japanese Americans; Scrapbooks
Scrapbooks
- Yoshito Fujii's notes on Japanese History in the Northwest, ca. 1610-1930, Before 1972; 1582-001
  Access restricted: For terms of access contact Special Collections.
  Y. Fujii, Apr. 12, 1971.
- Yoshito Fujii papers, 1942-1945; 1582-002
  The collection consists of a three-volume scrapbook that contains, among scores of items, minutes, memoranda, reports, and correspondence dating from 1942 to 1945.
  Open to all users.
  Y. Fujii, Dec. 16, 1979.
  - WRA Housing Division
    - Policy and Regulations (Volume I, Page 5-6)
    - Clearance Procedure (Volume I, Page 7)
    - Outside Visitors (Volume I, Page 8)
    - Adjustment Board (Volume I, Page 9)
    - Housing Census (Volume I, Page 11)
    - Adjustment (Volume I, Page 13-14)
    - Short Term Leaves (Volume I, Page 16)
    - Segregation and Adjustment (Volume I, Page 17-18)
    - Housing for Community Activities (Volume I, Page 19)
    - 2000 from the Tule Lake Camp (Volume I, Page 20-23)
    - List of Repatriates (Volume I, Page 25)
    - Sample of Case Workers' Reports (Volume I, Page 26)
  - Consumers' Cooperative Enterprise
    - Minutes of Inter-Project Cooperative Conference (Volume I, Page 27)
    - Inter-Project Communication Memos (Volume I, Page 28-33)
    - Balance Sheet of Consumer Enterprise, Topaz, Utah (Volume I, Page 34)
    - Minidoka Consumers' Cooperative Membership Dues (Volume I, Page 35)
    - Inter-Project Communication (Volume I, Page 36-37)
    - Letter to Mr. Gerald Richardson, Washington, D.C. (Volume I, Page 38-39)
    - Federal State Unemployment Tax (Volume I, Page 40)
    - Operating Agreement, Enterprise WRA (Volume I, Page 41-42)
    - Articles of Incorporation of the Minidoka Consumers' Cooperative (Volume I, Page 43)
    - Additional Shoe Ration Currency (Volume I, Page 48)
    - Administrative Instruction No. 28, Financial Condition of Enterprise (Volume I, Page 49)
    - Letter from Otto Rossman, Sr. Advisor (Volume I, Page 50-51)
    - Fidelity National Bank's Letter (Volume I, Page 52)
    - Question on Employment Tax Liability (Volume I, Page 53)
    - US Securities Exchange Commission
      - Subject: Public Offering (Volume I, Page 54-56)
      - Reply (Volume I, Page 57)
      - Regional Office, Seattle, Wash. (Volume I, Page 58-59)
    - Special License (Volume I, Page 60-62)
    - Operating Agreement (Volume I, Page 64-66)
    - Letter of Recommendation for Mr. Taikichi Fujihara (Volume I, Page 67)
    - Administrative Instruction No. 94, Issuance of Work Clothing (Volume I, Page 68-69)
    - Movies Showing (Volume I, Page 70)
    - Patronage Dividends (Volume I, Page 71)
    - Movies, Flowershop, Fish Store, and Newspaper (Volume I, Page 72)
    - Inter-Project Consumers' Enterprise, Employment and Its Rating - Charter (Volume I, Page 73)
    - Minutes of Federation of Business - Enterprise Conference (Volume I, Page 74-87)
    - Montgomery Ward, Catalogs (Volume I, Page 88)
    - Administrative Notices (Volume I, Page 89-91)
    - Joint Meeting with the Administrative Staff Members (Volume I, Page 92-93)
    - Membership - Stamp Tax (Volume I, Page 94)
    - License and Job Classification for Laborers (Volume I, Page 95-96)
    - Petition from Barbers and Data (Volume I, Page 97-99)
    - Memo - Fish Supplies in the Diet (Volume I, Page 100)
    - Corporation License Tax (Volume I, Page 101)
    - Chicago Conference (Volume I, Page 102)
    - Inter-Office Memo (Volume I, Page 104-105)
    - Operating Statement (Volume I, Page 106)
    - Balance Sheet as of Dec. 31, 1943 (Volume I, Page 107)
  - Community Government
    - Organization (Volume I, Page 108-111)
    - Election Rules for Community Council (Volume I, Page 112)
    - First Community Council (Volume I, Page 113)
    - Officers and Committee Members (Volume I, Page 114-116)
    - Minutes of the Community Council Meeting, March 9, 1944 (Volume I, Page 117-121)
    - Minutes of the Community Council Meeting, March 14, 1944 (Volume I, Page 121-122)
    - Joint Meeting of Community Council and Block Commissioners, March 21, 1944 (Volume I, Page 123-130)
    - Minutes of the Community Council Meeting, March 28, 1944 (Volume I, Page 131-135)
    - Supplemental Reports (Volume I, Page 136-138)
  - Minidoka Community Government
    - Minutes
      - Community Council Meeting, April 4, 1944 (Volume II, Page 3-7)
      - Community Council Meeting, May 10, 1944 (Volume II, Page 8-9)
      - Mediation Committee Meeting, Jan. 7, 1944 (Volume II, Page 10-16)
      - Block Delegates Meeting, Jan 8, 1944 (Volume II, Page 17-19)
      - Mediation Committee Meeting, Jan. 9, 1944 (Volume II, Page 20-21)
      - Joint Meeting of Mediation Committee and Sanitation Representatives, Jan. 10, 1944 (Volume II, Page 22-25)
      - Joint Meeting of Boilermen, Janitors and Janitoresses, Jan. 10, 1944 (Volume II, Page 26-28)
    - Letter Addressed to Mr. Stafford, Project Director (Volume II, Page 29)
    - Summaries of Our Observation on the Dispute Between the Administration and Maintenance Workers (Volume II, Page 30-37)
    - Agendas
      - Regular Monthly Joint Meeting with the Block Commissioners, May 16, 1944 (Volume II, Page 38)
      - Special Community Council Meeting, May 29, 1944 (Volume II, Page 39)
      - Special Community Council Meeting, June 6, 1944 (Volume II, Page 40)
      - Special Joint Meeting with the Block Commissioners, June 7, 1944 (Volume II, Page 41)
      - Special Community Council Meeting, June 14, 1944 (Volume II, Page 42)
      - Regular Monthly Joint Meeting with the Block Commissioners, June 20, 1944 (Volume II, Page 43)
      - Regular Monthly Joint Meeting with the Block Commissioners, June 18, 1944 (Volume II, Page 44)
    - Minutes
      - Special Joint Meeting of Community Council (Old New Members), Sept. 5, 1944 (Volume II, Page 48-50)
      - Community Council Meeting, Sept. 26, 1944 (Volume II, Page 51-52)
      - Community Council Meeting, Oct. 2, 1944 (Volume II, Page 53-56)
      - Special Council Meeting, Oct. 2, 1944 (Volume II, Page 57-58)
      - Community Council Meeting, Oct. 24, 1944 (Volume II, Page 61-62)
      - Special Community Council Meeting, Oct. 26, 1944 (Volume II, Page 63-64)
      - Community Council Meeting, Nov. 7, 1944 (Volume II, Page 65-67)
      - Community Council Meeting, Nov. 28, 1944 (Volume II, Page 68-69)
      - Special Community Council Meeting, Dec. 4, 1944 (Volume II, Page 70-71)
      - Community Council Meeting, Dec. 19, 1944 (Volume II, Page 72-73)
      - Community Council Meeting, Jan. 16, 1945 (Volume II, Page 74-75)
      - Meeting of Community Council and the Block Commissioners with Mr. S. T. Kimball, Jan. 4, 1945 (Volume II, Page 76-80)
      - The Japanese Translation of the Minutes Mentioned Above (Volume II, Page 81-86)
    - Summary of WRA Policies and Procedures for the Final Phase of the Relocation Program (Volume II, Page 87-96)
    - Minutes of Meeting of the Community Council and the Block Commissioners, with Mr. D. S. Myer, National Director, Feb. 19, 1945 (Volume II, Page 97-124)
    - Public Announcement Made by Mr. Dillon S. Myer, National Director, early 1945 (Volume II, Page 125)
    - Report to Mr. Myer from Residents of Minidoka, Feb.19, 1945 (Volume II, Page 126-132)
    - Letter from Mr. Stafford to Community Council Chairman (Volume II, Page 133)
    - Letter to Mr. Stafford from Stafford School PTA (Volume II, Page 134-135)
    - Minutes of Joint Meeting of the Old and New Community Council and the Block Commissioners, Mar. 12, 1945 (Volume II, Page 143-144)
  - Supplementary Documents
    - Center Regulations, July 10, 1942 (Volume III, Page 2-32)
    - Labor Dispute - Between Administration and Maintenance Workers
      - Letter to Mr. Stafford, Proj. Director, Jan. 7, 1944 (Volume III, Page 34)
      - The Arbitration Committee's Observation and Recommendations (Volume III, Page 35-37)
      - Memo to Janitorial Service Workers (Volume III, Page 38)
      - Copy of Teletype Message from Mr. Myer, WRA Wa (Volume III, Page 39)
      - Letter from Mr. Stafford to Community Council (Volume III, Page 40)
      - Recommendation from Council Mediation Committee (Volume III, Page 41)
      - Letter from Mr. Stafford to Mr. Hatade [i.e., Hatate], Supervisor, and All Maintenance Employees (Volume III, Page 42)
      - Minutes of Mediation Committee Meeting, Jan. 7, 1944 (Volume III, Page 43)
      - Minutes of Joint Meeting with Mr.Stafford, Jan. 7, 1944 (Volume III, Page 44-49)
      - Minutes of Block Delegates, Jan. 8, 1944 (Volume III, Page 50-52)
      - Minutes of Mediation Committee, Jan. 9, 1944 (2:00 p.m.) (Volume III, Page 53)
      - Minutes of Mediation Committee, Jan. 9, 1944 (4:30 p.m.) (Volume III, Page 54)
      - Minutes of Joint of Mediation Committee and Sanitation Representatives, Jan. 10, 1944 (10 a.m.) (Volume III, Page 55-58)
      - Minutes of Joint Meeting of Boilermen, Janitors, Janitoresses, Jan. 10, 1944 (3:00 p.m.) (Volume III, Page 59-61)
    - Labor Dispute - In the Construction of Project Gymnasium
      - Memorandum from Mr. Stafford to Council Chairman (Volume III, Page 62)
      - Memorandum to Mr. Rawlings, Ass. Proj. Director in Charge of Operations, Oct. 20, 1944 (Volume III, Page 63)
      - Our Reply to Mr. Stafford, Oct. 27, 1944 (Volume III, Page 64-67)
      - Letter from Mr. Stafford, Oct. 27, 1944 (Volume III, Page 68)
      - Copy of Memo to Mr. Rawlings, Oct. 25, 1944 (Volume III, Page 69)
      - Copy of Letter from Mr. Plank, Sr. Engineer, to Mr. Rawlings, Oct. 26, 1944 (Volume III, Page 70-71)
      - Copy of a Letter from Mr. Myer to Mr. Stafford, Oct. 20, 1944 (Volume III, Page 72)
      - Letter from Mr. Stafford to Community Council Chairman, Nov. 13, 1944 (Volume III, Page 73-76)
      - Diagram of Relationship of All Concerned and Their Responsibilities in Gym. Construction (Volume III, Page 77)
      - Notice of Meeting to Mr. Omura, Nov. 13, 1944 (Volume III, Page 78)
      - Japanese Recruiting Notice for Work Crew (Volume III, Page 79)
      - Copy of Teletype Message from Mr. Stafford to Mr. Myer, Nov. 15, 1944 (Volume III, Page 80)
      - Signed Petition from Hunt High School Student Council to Community Council Chairman, Nov. 17, 1944 (Volume III, Page 81)
      - Office Memorandum from Mr. Stafford to Community Council Chairman, Nov. 17, 1944 (Volume III, Page 82-83)
      - Teletype to Mr. Myer, Wn., Nov. 20, 1944 (Volume III, Page 84-86)
      - Letter from Mr. Stafford to Council Chairman, Dec. 2, 1944 (Volume III, Page 87-88)
    - Closing Pickling Plants and Some Labor Problems
      - Letter to Mr. Davidson, Ass. Proj. Director, in Charge of Operation, Mar. 11, 1944 (Volume III, Page 89)
      - Letter from Mr. Miller, Acting Proj. Director, to Council Chairman, Mar. 14, 1944 (Volume III, Page 90-91)
      - Minutes of Joint Meeting of the Pickling Plantworkers and Representatives of the Farm Division, Mar. 18, 1944 (Volume III, Page 92-95)
    - Suspension of the Community Activities Program
      - Letter to Mr. Stafford, Oct. 31, 1944 (Volume III, Page 96-98)
      - Letter from Mr. Stafford to Council Chairman, Nov. 10, 1944 (Volume III, Page 99-100)
    - Disbanding of the Emergency Crew Set-up
      - Letter from Mr. Stafford to Council Chairman, Nov. 27, 1944 (Volume III, Page 101)
      - Letter from Mr. Stafford to Council Chairman, Nov. 29, 1944 (Volume III, Page 102)
      - Letter from Mr. Stafford to Council Chairman, Dec. 12, 1944 (Volume III, Page 102-106)
    - Coal Hauling Operation Labor Problem
      - Letter from Mr. Stafford to Council Chairman, Nov. 30, 1944 (Volume III, Page 107)
      - Letter from Mr. Stafford to Council Chairman, Dec. 7, 1944 (Volume III, Page 108-109)
      - Copy of Memo to Mr. Gooding, Dec. 6, 1944 (Volume III, Page 110)
      - Memo from Mr. Barrett, Proj. Attorney, Dec. 9, 1944 (Volume III, Page 111)
    - Special Report to Mr. Kimball, Community Org. Advisor W.R.A. (Volume III, Page 112-114)